We are all activists now.
نحن جميعا نشطاء الآن.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
I'll just stop here.
سوف أتوقف هنا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
From the families who are fighting to maintain funding for public schools,
من العائلات التي تقاتل للحفاظ على تمويل المدارس الحكومية،
the tens of thousands of people who joined Occupy Wall Street
وعشرات الآلاف من الأشخاص الذين شاركوا في احتلال "وال ستريت"
or marched with Black Lives Matter
أو تظاهروا مع "بلاك لايفز ماتر"
to protest police brutality against African Americans,
للاعتراض على وحشية الشرطة ضد الأفريقيين الأمريكيين
families that join rallies,
والعائلات التي تنضم إلى الحشود
pro-life and pro-choice,
المؤيدة للحياة وحرية الاختيار،
those of us who are afraid
وأولئك بيننا الذين يخافون
that our friends and neighbors are going to be deported
أن يتم ترحيل أصدقائنا وجيراننا
or that they'll be added to lists
أو أن تتم إضافتهم إلى قوائم
because they are Muslim,
لأنهم مسلمون،
people who advocate for gun rights and for gun control
والأشخاص الذين يؤيدون حق حمل السلاح والسيطرة على السلاح
and the millions of people who joined the women's marches
وملايين الأشخاص الذين شاركوا في المسيرات النسائية
all across the country this last January.
في جميع أنحاء البلاد يناير الماضي.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
We are all activists now,
نحن جميعا نشطاء الآن،
and that means that we all have something to worry about from surveillance.
وذلك يعني أن لدينا ما نقلق بشأنه بخصوص المراقبة.
Surveillance means government collection and use
المراقبة تعني جمع واستخدام الحكومة
of private and sensitive data about us.
لمعلومات خاصة وحساسة عنا.
And surveillance is essential
والمراقبة ضرورية
to law enforcement and to national security.
لإنفاذ القانون وللأمن القومي.
But the history of surveillance
ولكن تاريخ المراقبة
is one that includes surveillance abuses
يتضمن انتهاكات
where this sensitive information has been used against people
حيث يتم استخدام هذه المعلومات الحساسة ضد الأشخاص
because of their race,
بسبب عرقهم،
their national origin,
أو أصولهم القومية،
their sexual orientation,
أو توجهاتهم الجنسية،
and in particular, because of their activism,
وعلى وجه الخصوص بسبب نشاطهم،
their political beliefs.
ومعتقداتهم السياسية.
About 53 years ago,
منذ 53 عاما،
Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. gave his "I have a dream" speech
ألقى د. (مارتن لوثر كينج) الابن خطابه بعنوان "لدي حلم"
on the Mall in Washington.
في ساحة بواشنطن.
And today the ideas behind this speech of racial equality and tolerance
واليوم الأفكار وراء هذا الخطاب من مساواة عرقية وتسامح
are so noncontroversial
غير مثيرة للجدل
that my daughters study the speech in third grade.
حتى أن بناتي يدرسن الخطاب في الصف الثالث.
But at the time,
ولكن حينها،
Dr. King was extremely controversial.
كان د. (كينج) مثيرا للجدل للغاية
The legendary and notorious FBI Director J. Edgar Hoover believed,
مدير "الإف بي آي" الأسطوري (ج. إدغار هوفر) كان يعتقد،
or wanted to believe,
أو أراد أن يعتقد،
that the Civil Rights Movement was a Soviet communist plot
أن حركة الحقوق المدنية كانت مؤامرة شيوعية سوفيتية.
intended to destabilize the American government.
تهدف إلى زعزعة استقرار الحكومة الأمريكية.
And so Hoover had his agents put bugs in Dr. King's hotel rooms,
لذا قام (هوفر) وعملاؤه بزرع أجهزة تنصت في غرفة فندق د. (كينج)
and those bugs picked up conversations between civil rights leaders
والتقطت هذه الأجهزة محادثات بين قادة حركة الحقوق المدنية
talking about the strategies and tactics of the Civil Rights Movement.
حيث يتحدثون عن الخطط والإجراءات لحركة الحقوق المدنية
They also picked up sounds of Dr. King
والتقطوا أيضا صوت د.(كينج)
having sex with women who were not his wife,
يمارس الجنس مع نساء غير زوجته،
and J. Edgar Hoover saw the opportunity here
ورأى (ج. إدغار) هوفر فرصته هنا
to discredit and undermine the Civil Rights Movement.
لتشويه سمعة وتقويض حركة الحقوق المدنية.
The FBI sent a package of these recordings
أرسلت "الإف بي آي" طردا بهذه التسجيلات
along with a handwritten note to Dr. King,
مع مذكرة بخط اليد إلى د. (كينج)
and a draft of this note was found in FBI archives years later,
وقد وجدت مسودة هذه المذكرة في محفوظات "الإف بي آي" بعد أعوام
and the letter said,
وكتب في الرسالة،
"You are no clergyman and you know it.
"أنت لست قسا وأنت تعلم ذلك.
King, like all frauds, your end is approaching."
مثل جميع المخادعين يا (كينج) فقد اقتربت نهايتك."
The letter even seemed to encourage Dr. King to commit suicide,
حتى أن الخطاب يبدو أنه يشجع د.( كينج) على الانتحار
saying, "King, there is only one thing left for you to do.
قائلا: "بقي شيء واحد فقط لفعله يا (كينج)
You know what it is.
وأنت تعلم ما هو.
You better take it before your filthy, abnormal, fraudulent self
من الأفضل أن تنهيها قبل أن تصبح نفسك القذرة الشاذة الاحتيالية
is bared to the nation."
مكشوفة أمام الأمة."
But the important thing is,
ولكن الشيء الأهم هو،
Dr. King was not abnormal.
أن د. (كينج) لم يكن مختلفاً
Every one of us has something that we want to hide from somebody.
فكل شخص منا يملك شيئا يريد إخفاءه عن الآخرين
And even more important,
وأيضا أهم من ذلك،
J. Edgar Hoover wasn't abnormal either.
لم يكن (ج. إدغار هوفر) مختلفاً أيضا
The history of surveillance abuses
فتاريخ انتهاكات المراقبة
is not the history of one bad, megalomaniacal man.
ليس تاريخ رجل واحد سيء مهووس.
Throughout his decades at the FBI,
خلال عقود من عمله في "الإف بي آي"
J. Edgar Hoover enjoyed the support of the presidents that he served,
استمتع (ج. إدغار هوفر) بدعم الرؤساء الذين خدمهم،
Democratic and Republican alike.
الديموقراطيين والجمهوريين على السواء.
After all, it was John F. Kennedy and his brother Robert Kennedy
في النهاية كان (جون ف. كينيدي) وأخيه (روبرت كينيدي)
who knew about and approved the surveillance of Dr. King.
الذين علموا ووافقوا على مراقبة د. (كينج).
Hoover ran a program called COINTELPRO for 15 years
أدار (هوفر) برنامج يدعى "كوينتيلبرو" لمدة 15 عام
which was designed to spy on and undermine civic groups
والذي صمم للتجسس على وتقويض الجماعات المدنية
that were devoted to things like civil rights,
التي كانت مكرسة لأشياء مثل الحقوق المدنية،
the Women's Rights Movement,
وحركة حقوق المرأة،
and peace groups and anti-war movements.
والحركات الداعمة للسلام.
And the surveillance didn't stop there.
ولم تتوقف المراقبة عند ذلك.
Lyndon Baines Johnson,
قام (ليندون بينس جونسون)
during the election campaign,
خلال الحملة الانتخابية
had the campaign airplane of his rival Barry Goldwater bugged
بالتجسس على طائرة منافسه (باري جولدواتر)
as part of his effort to win that election.
كجزء من جهوده للفوز بالانتخابات
And then, of course, there was Watergate.
ثم كان هناك "واترجيت"
Burglars were caught
تم القبض على مقتحمين
breaking into the Democratic National Committee headquarters
في مقر اللجنة الوطنية الديموقراطية
at the Watergate Hotel,
في فندق "واترجيت"
the Nixon administration was involved in covering up the burglary,
وشاركت إدارة (نيكسون) في التستر على الاقتحام،
and eventually Nixon had to step down as president.
وأخيرا اضطر (نيكسون) إلى التنحي عن الرئاسة.
COINTELPRO and Watergate were a wake-up call for Americans.
"كوينتيلبرو" و"واترجيت" كانوا نداء الصحوة للأمريكيين.
Surveillance was out of control
المراقبة كانت خارج السيطرة
and it was being used to squelch political challengers.
وكانت تستخدم لإسقاط المنافسين السياسيين.
And so Americans rose to the occasion
وتصدى الأمريكيون للحدث
and what we did was we reformed surveillance law.
وما فعلناه هو إصلاح قانون المراقبة.
And the primary tool we used to reform surveillance law
والأداة الأولى التي استخدمت لإصلاح قانون المراقبة
was to require a search warrant
هي طلب مذكرة تفتيش
for the government to be able to get access to our phone calls and our letters.
لكي يمكن للحكومة الوصول إلى محادثاتنا الهاتفية وخطاباتنا.
Now, the reason why a search warrant is important
الآن، سبب كون مذكرة التفتيش هامة
is because it interposes a judge
هو أنها تُشرك قاضي
in the relationship between investigators and the citizens,
في العلاقة بين المحققين والمواطنين،
and that judge's job is to make sure
ووظيفة هذا القاضي هي التأكد
that there's good cause for the surveillance,
أن هناك سببًا وجيهًا للمراقبة،
that the surveillance is targeted at the right people,
وأن المراقبة تستهدف الشخص الصحيح،
and that the information that's collected
وأن المعلومات التي يتم جمعها
is going to be used for legitimate government purposes
سوف تستخدم لأغراض حكومية مشروعة
and not for discriminatory ones.
وليس بغرض التمييز.
This was our system,
كان هذا نظامنا،
and what this means is
وما يعنيه ذلك
that President Obama did not wiretap Trump Tower.
أن الرئيس (أوباما) لم يتنصت على "برج ترمب".
The system is set up to prevent something like that from happening
فالنظام مصمم لمنع حدوث ذلك
without a judge being involved.
بدون إشراك قاض.
But what happens when we're not talking about phone calls or letters anymore?
ولكن ماذا يحدث عندما لا نتكلم عن محادثات الهاتف والخطابات؟
Today, we have technology
اليوم لدينا تقنيات
that makes it cheap and easy for the government to collect information
تجعل من السهل والرخيص على الحكومة جمع معلومات
on ordinary everyday people.
عن الناس العاديين.
Your phone call records
سجل مكالماتك الهاتفية
can reveal whether you have an addiction,
يمكن أن تكشف إن كان لديك إدمان،
what your religion is,
وما هو دينك،
what charities you donate to,
وما الجهات التي تتبرع لها،
what political candidate you support.
وأي مرشح سياسي تدعمه.
And yet, our government collected, dragnet-style,
ومع ذلك جمعت حكومتنا - على غرار المصيدة -
Americans' calling records for years.
سجلات مكالمات الأمريكيين لأعوام.
In 2012, the Republican National Convention
في 2012، قام المؤتمر الوطني الجمهوري
highlighted a new technology it was planning to use,
بإبراز تقنية جديدة يخططون لاستخدامها،
facial recognition,
وهي التعرف على الوجوه،
to identify people who were going to be in the crowd
للتعرف على الأشخاص في الزحام
who might be activists or troublemakers
الذين يمكن أن يكونوا نشطاء أو مسببي متاعب
and to stop them ahead of time.
وتوقيفهم فورا.
Today, over 50 percent of American adults
اليوم، 50 بالمائة من البالغين الأمريكيين
have their faceprint in a government database.
توجد بصمة وجوههم في قاعدة بيانات حكومية.
The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives
إدارة الكحول والتبغ والأسلحة النارية والمتفجرات
concocted a plan
وضعت خطة
to find out what Americans were going to gun shows
للتعرف على الأمريكيين الذين كانوا يذهبون إلى عروض السلاح
by using license plate detectors
باستخدام كواشف عن لوحات الرخصة
to scan the license plates of cars
عن طريق مسح لوحات ترخيص السيارات
that were in the parking lots of these events.
التي كانت في مواقف السيارات في هذه الأحداث.
Today, we believe that over 70 percent of police departments
اليوم، نعتقد أن أكثر من 70 بالمائة من إدارات الشرطة
have automatic license plate detection technology
يملكون تقنية كشف تلقائي عن لوحات الرخصة
that they're using to track people's cars as they drive through town.
ويستخدمونها لتتبع السيارات عبر المدينة.
And all of this information,
وكل هذه المعلومات،
the license plates, the faceprints,
لوحات الرخصة، وبصمة الوجه،
the phone records,
وسجلات المكالمات،
your address books, your buddy lists,
وكتاب العناوين، وقوائم الأصدقاء،
the photos that you upload to Dropbox or Google Photos,
الصور التي تحملها إلى "دروب بوكس" أو "صور جوجل"
and sometimes even your chats and your emails
وأحيانا حتى محادثاتك وبريدك الإلكتروني
are not protected by a warrant requirement.
ليست محمية بطلب مذكرة.
So what that means is we have all of this information on regular people
وما يعنيه ذلك هو أن لدينا هذه المعلومات عن أشخاص عاديين
that's newly available at very low expense.
متاحة بتكلفة منخفضة.
It is the golden age for surveillance.
وهذا هو العصر الذهبي للمراقبة.
Now, every parent is going to understand what this means.
الآن، جميع الآباء سيفهمون معنى ذلك.
When you have a little baby
عندما يكون لديك طفلة صغيرة
and the baby's young,
والطفلة صغيرة،
that child is not able to climb out of its crib.
لا تستطيع التسلق خارج فراشها.
But eventually your little girl gets older
ولكن في النهاية تصبح ابنتك أكبر
and she's able to climb out of the crib,
وتكون قادرة على الخروج من فراشها،
but you tell her, "Don't climb out of the crib. OK?"
ولكنك تخبرها "لا تتسلقي خارج فراشك. حسنا؟"
And every parent knows what's going to happen.
وجميع الآباء يعلمون ما سيحدث.
Some of those babies are going to climb out of the crib.
أحد هؤلاء الأطفال سيخرج من فراشه.
Right? That's the difference between ability and permission.
أليس كذلك؟ وهذا هو الفرق بين القدرة والإذن.
Well, the same thing is true with the government today.
حسنا، الأمر نفسه ينطبق على الحكومة
It used to be that our government didn't have the ability
لم يكن لدى الحكومة القدرة
to do widespread, massive surveillance on hundreds of millions of Americans
للقيام بمراقبة واسعة النطاق على مئات الملايين من الأميركيين
and then abuse that information.
ثم تسيء استخدام المعلومات.
But now our government has grown up,
ولكن الآن وقد نضجت حكومتنا،
and we have that technology today.
ولدينا هذه التقنيات اليوم.
The government has the ability,
فلدى الحكومة القدرة،
and that means the law is more important than ever before.
وذلك يعني أن القانون أصبح أكثر أهمية مما سبق.
The law is supposed to say
القانون يفترض أن يقول
when the government has permission to do it,
متى يصبح لدى الحكومة الإذن لفعل ذلك،
and it's supposed to ensure that there's some kind of ramification.
وينبغي أن يضمن وجود نوع من العاقبة.
We notice when those laws are broken
فنحن نلاحظ عند كسر هذه القوانين
and there's some of kind of ramification or punishment.
مع وجود نوع من العاقبة أو العقاب.
The law is more important than ever because we are now living in a world
فالقانون أهم الآن مما سبق لأننا نعيش في عالم
where only rules are stopping the government
حيث فقط القواعد تمنع الحكومات
from abusing this information.
من إساءة استخدام هذه المعلومات
But the law has fallen down on the job.
ولكن القانون قد قصر في عمله.
Particularly since September 11 the law has fallen down on the job,
خاصة منذ 11 سبتمبر فإن القانون قد قصر في عمله،
and we do not have the rules in place that we need.
وليس لدينا القواعد حيث نحتاجها.
And we are seeing the ramifications of that.
ونرى عاقبة ذلك.
So fusion centers are these joint task forces
مراكز الانصهار هي فرق العمل المشتركة
between local, state and federal government
بين المحليات والولاية والحكومة الفيدرالية
that are meant to ferret out domestic terrorism.
التي يفترض أن تكشف الإرهاب المحلي.
And what we've seen is fusion center reports
وما رأيناه هو تقارير مراكز الانصهار
that say that you might be dangerous
التي تقول أنك ربما تكون خطيرا
if you voted for a third-party candidate,
إذا قمت بالتصويت لمرشح مستقل،
or you own a "Don't Tread On Me" flag,
أو إذا كنت تملك راية "لا تخطو فوقي"
or you watched movies that are anti-tax.
أو شاهدت أفلاما ضد فرض الضريبة.
These same fusion centers have spied on Muslim community groups' reading lists
ومراكز الانصهار هذه تجسست على قوائم القراءة لمجموعات المجتمع المسلم
and on Quakers who are resisting military recruiting in high schools.
وعلى "الكويكرز" الذين يقاومون التجنيد العسكري في المدارس الثانوية.
The Internal Revenue Service has disproportionately audited
وقامت دائرة الإيرادات الداخلية بشكل غير متناسب بالتدقيق
groups that have "Tea Party" or "Patriot" in their name.
في مجموعات تحمل عبارات "حزب الشاي" أو "وطني" في اسمها.
And now customs and border patrol
والآن الجمارك والدوريات الحدودية
is stopping people as they come into the country
توقف الأشخاص عند دخولهم البلاد
and demanding our social networking passwords
وتطلب كلمات المرور لشبكاتنا الاجتماعية
which will allow them to see who our friends are,
ما سيمكنهم من معرفة من هم أصدقاؤنا،
what we say
وماذا نقول
and even to impersonate us online.
وحتى انتحال شخصياتنا على الانترنت.
Now, civil libertarians like myself
الآن، التحريريون المدنيون مثلي
have been trying to draw people's attention to these things
كانوا يحاولون لفت انتباه الناس لهذه الأمور
and fighting against them for years.
ويحاربون ضدها لسنوات.
This was a huge problem during the Obama administration,
وقد كانت مشكلة كبرى خلال إدارة (أوباما)،
but now the problem is worse.
ولكن الآن أصبحت المشكلة أسوأ.
When the New York Police Department
عندما تقوم إدارة شرطة "نيويورك"
spies on Muslims
بالتجسس على المسلمين
or a police department uses license plate detectors
أو تستخدم إدارة الشرطة كواشف للوحات الرخصة
to find out where the officers' spouses are
لمعرفة أين أزواج الضباط
or those sorts of things,
أو هذا النوع من الأشياء،
that is extremely dangerous.
فذلك يعد خطيرا للغاية.
But when a president repurposes the power
ولكن عندما يقوم الرئيس بإعادة توطين السلطة
of federal surveillance and the federal government
من المراقبة الفيدرالية والحكومة الفيدرالية
to retaliate against political opposition,
للانتقام من المعارضة السياسية،
that is a tyranny.
فهذا هو الطغيان،
And so we are all activists now,
وهكذا، فجميعنا نشطاء الآن
and we all have something to fear from surveillance.
وجميعنا نملك ما نخشاه بخصوص المراقبة.
But just like in the time of Dr. Martin Luther King,
ولكن كما في زمن د. (مارتن لوثر كينج)
we can reform the way things are.
يمكننا إصلاح هذه الأمور.
First of all, use encryption.
أولا، عليكم استخدام التشفير.
Encryption protects your information
فالتشفير يحمي معلوماتكم
from being inexpensively and opportunistically collected.
من جمعها بطرق رخيصة وانتهازية.
It rolls back the golden age for surveillance.
وبذلك يتراجع العصر الذهبي للمراقبة.
Second, support surveillance reform.
ثانيا، ادعموا إصلاح المراقبة.
Did you know that if you have a friend
هل تعلمون أنه إذا كان لديكم صديق
who works for the French or German governments
يعمل في الحكومة الفرنسية أو الألمانية
or for an international human rights group
أو في مجموعة حقوق إنسان دولية
or for a global oil company
أو في شركة نفط عالمية
that your friend is a valid foreign intelligence target?
أن صديقكم هدف صالح للاستخبارات الأجنبية؟
And what that means is that when you have conversations with that friend,
وما يعنيه ذلك هو أنكم متى أجريتم حديث مع هذا الصديق،
the US government may be collecting that information.
فربما تجمع حكومة الولايات الأمريكية هذه المعلومات.
And when that information is collected,
وعندما يتم جمع هذه المعلومات،
even though it's conversations with Americans,
على الرغم من كونها محادثات بين أمريكيين،
it can then be funneled to the FBI
يمكن تسريبها إلى "الإف بي آي"
where the FBI is allowed to search through it
حيث يسمح لهم بالبحث فيها
without getting a warrant,
دون الحصول على إذن،
without probable cause,
ودون سبب وجيه،
looking for information about Americans
البحث في معلومات الأمريكيين
and whatever crimes we may have committed
وأيا كانت الجرائم التي ارتكبناها
with no need to document any kind of suspicion.
دون الحاجة إلى توثيق أي نوع من الشك.
The law that allows some of this to happen
القانون الذي يسمح بحدوث ذلك
is called Section 702 of the FISA Amendments Act,
يسمى القسم 702 من تعديلات قانون مراقبة الاستخبارات الأجنبية،
and we have a great opportunity this year,
ونحن لدينا فرصة هذا العام
because Section 702 is going to expire at the end of 2017,
لأن القسم 702 سوف ينتهي بنهاية عام 2017،
which means that Congress's inertia is on our side
ما يعني أن تعطل "الكونجرس" في صالحنا
if we want reform.
إذا أردنا الإصلاح.
And we can pressure our representatives
ويمكننا الضغط على ممثلينا
to actually implement important reforms to this law
لإجراء تعديلات هامة في هذا القانون
and protect our data from this redirection and misuse.
وحماية بياناتنا من إعادة التوجيه وإساءة الاستخدام.
And finally, one of the reasons why things have gotten so out of control
وأخيرا، أحد أسباب خروج الأمور عن السيطرة
is because so much of what happens with surveillance --
هو أن جزء كبير مما يحدث في المراقبة
the technology, the enabling rules and the policies
التقنية وقواعد وسياسات الإتاحة
that are either there or not there to protect us --
الموجودة أو غير موجودة لحمايتنا
are secret or classified.
هي سرية أو مصنفة كذلك.
We need transparency, and we need to know as Americans
نحن بحاجة إلى الشفافية وإلى أن نعلم كأمريكيين
what the government is doing in our name
ما تفعله الحكومة باسمنا
so that the surveillance that takes place and the use of that information
بحيث تصبح المراقبة التي تحدث واستخدام المعلومات
is democratically accounted for.
مسببة ديموقراطيا.
We are all activists now,
جميعنا نشطاء الآن،
which means that we all have something to worry about from surveillance.
ذلك يعني أننا نملك ما نخشاه بخصوص المراقبة
But like in the time of Dr. Martin Luther King,
ولكن كما في زمن د. مارتن لوثر كينج
there is stuff that we can do about it.
هناك ما يمكننا فعله في هذا الشأن
So please join me, and let's get to work.
لذا رجاء انضموا لي ولنبدأ العمل.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)